#### Contact

301 University Blvd. Route 0170 Galveston, Texas 77555 4097478772 (Work) tcupit@utmb.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/tammycupit-1a150146 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Internal Medicine

**Pediatrics** 

**Public Speaking** 

#### Certifications

Non-Violent Crisis Intervention Instructor

Social + Emotional Intelligence Certification

2013-2018 American Nurses Credentialing Center (ANCC) -Nursing Professional Development

#### **Publications**

Marshall, D., Davis, P., Cupit, T., Hilt, T., Baer, J. & Bonificio, B. (2014). Achieving Added Value in a Knowledge-Intense Organization: One Hospital's Journey. Nurse Leader 01/2014; 12(3): 36-42.

The Forgotten Families: A Needs Assessment on Children with Incarcerated Parents in Harris County, Texas

Acts of Indirect Aggression as Tactics of Hierarchy Negotiation Mediated by Personality Traits in Female Registered Nurses (Doctoral Dissertation).

Role of Research and Evidence-Based Practice Councils. In N. Albert (Ed.), Building and Sustaining a Hospital-Based Nursing Research Program

Assessing the Nurse Manager's Span of Control: A Partnership between Executive Leadership, Nurse Scientists and Clinicians

# **Tammy Cupit**

Director, Nursing Science & Innovation at The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston

Galveston, Texas

# Experience

The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston 6 years 9 months

Director, Nursing Science & Innovation April 2018 - Present (2 years 4 months) Galveston, Texas

Director of Nursing Research November 2013 - Present (6 years 9 months) UTMB Health System

- Provide nursing mentorship and direction in designing, conducting and disseminating nursing research
- Develop, monitor and maintain research-focused educational activities and in-services
- Develop curriculum for research training programs for nurses
- Provide evaluation of learning activities through testing and surveys
- Develop online educational research presentations to meet the needs of various clinical sites
- Serve on nursing policy, professional development and education, research and practice councils
- · Assist with development of data collection tools and processes
- Precept, mentor and guide BSN nursing students in psychiatric, community, health assessment courses
- Precept, mentor and guide DNP and PhD nursing students in research/ capstone projects
- Mentor and precept PhD students in research practica
- Develop data driven patient outcomes measures specific to identified health system areas
- Participate as a doctoral dissertation committee member as applicable

## Education

The University of Texas Medical Branch at Galveston Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Nursing Education · (2008 - 2013)

UTMB Graduate School of Biomedical Sciences PhD, Nursing Education and Research · (2008 - 2013)